JESSE SMITH

WEB DEVELOPER

M: 021 080-72341 | E: j.t.a.smith26@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jesse-ta-smith/

GitHub: github.com/jesse-smith1

ABOUT ME

Hello, I am a full stack developer living in Wellington who has a hospitable personality and a passion for laughter and people. I enjoy working within a team environment discovering each person's strengths and personalities to come up with solutions.

I have 10+ years experience in customer service working in various teams, as a peer, mentor and leader to my colleagues. Throughout my career I have learnt how to clearly communicate, encourage and empathize with people from all sorts of backgrounds and am excited when to hear their progress.

I am now changing careers to the Tech industry as I want to surround myself with like minded people who also enjoy problem solving as a team and believe that this is a perfect industry to provide that.

EXPERIENCE

Dev Academy Aotearoa March 2023 - July 2023

- 15 weeks in an intensive bootcamp style learning environment that has challenged my
 patience, drive, curiosity, problem solving, self confidence, stress thresholds, public speaking
 skills, empathetic, technical and application skills.
- Over this short amount of time, I have come from no experience in IT to understanding how to write Javascript, TypeScript, connect APIs, create Databases, migrate and run seed data, Redux, React, SQL, CSS, HTML and Unit Testing.
- Dev Academy also teaches us various human skills such as reflection, how to provide and receive feedback, inclusivity, how to manage and recognise our own stress and communication.
- My team's final project ESC was an interactive digital escape room that involved 5 different games. I am so proud of how this turned out, the team I had was such a joy to work with and most importantly it was fun.

Travel | Oct 2022 - Jan 2023

Traveled throughout New Zealand from Auckland down to Queenstown.

ACCESS COMMUNITY HEALTH | Oct 2020 - Aug 2022 Team Leader | Call Centre

- Training staff in work procedures
- Deliver feedback for quality of work product to colleagues
- Leading a team of 45+ staff members to deliver service throughout the whole of New Zealand
- Create daily reports for all departments throughout New Zealand to assess how many clients require our services

• Take escalated calls from concerned clientele and clientele point of contacts.

MOJO, WELLINGTON I Oct 2018 - Feb 2020

Manager/Front of House/Barista

- Delivered an enhanced customer service experience with a friendly and professional demeanor
- Created staff rosters, ordered supplies and opened and closed multiple stores at the beginning and end of service hours

HOT POPPY CAFÉ, North Melbourne I March 2016-June 2018 Front of House/Barista

KARAKA CAFÉ, Wellington Waterfront I Feb 2014-Jan 2016 Waiter/Barista/Bartender

Training & Education:

Dev Academy Aotearoa, Wellington I March 2023 - July 2023

New Zealand Certificate in Applied Software Development

CAPITAL TRAINING, Wellington | Sept-Oct 2020

Contact Centre Training

 Contact Centre training including call volumes, pitch, tone, volume and pace, identifying customer queries, computer navigation, customer service, protocols, administration and conflict management

WHITIREIA POLYTECHNIC I 2014

Health Science Foundation Course

WELLINGTON INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY I 2009

Weltec Certificate in Barista

Referees:

Available on request